Matthew Hammond

Full stack developer

Matthew Hammond

BA2

Mobile: 07495174914

matthew.ian.hammond+jobs@gmail.com Github: https://github.com/ff7762

Website: https://ff7762.github.io/Portfolio/

Hi, I'm Matthew and I'm passionate about development. I've always played games and have been on the web and using technology since I was a young. I'm passionate for my career in something so close to me and influential to society. (And also really cool).

Skills

I have commercial experience in CSS, HTML, PHP, Python, Javascript/Jquery and MySQL. I am familiar with CSS libraries such as Bootstrap and skeleton for rapid prototyping. I have used the Python web framework Flask in personal projects. I have knowledge of Apache servers. I have a solid understanding of CI/build automation and have created CI builds according to the needs of project teams using python scripts with Jenkins and Bamboo. During my time at Mayden academy and my own time I have used React and Node. I am proficient in Docker. I am very familiar with Git and SVN. I am confident with the command line on Linux and Windows. I am proficient in SQL and SQLite. I have working knowledge of the Atlassian suite. I also have Knowledge of Illustrator and after Effects.

Previous employment

Software engineer july 2019 - March 2020, Altran

Customer Service / Ammerdown Jul 2018- Aug 2018, Writhlington

Customer Service / Subway Mar 2018- Dec 2018, Radstock

Projects

JavaScript Game/Long Dog Maze

Mayden-Academy/2019-jul-maze

Our team made a cursor maze game using JavaScript event handling and php from the ground up. You must navigate a long dog and avoid obstacles which use CSS animations.

Top Cat App

https://github.com/Mayden-Academy/2019-top-cat

Using cat API we built a cat app that uses php and sql as backend to store persistent cat data. It then uses a hydrator and displays cats of a breed upon user input, and allows users to select their favorite cat for each breed.

DarkHeresy-generator

https://github.com/ff7762/DarkHeresy-generator

An in development web-application that uses JS and PHP with the library TCPDF.

It is a redevelopment of an old tool from the early 2000's with new technology and features and will provide the RPG game system with functionality and accessibility that it currently lacks.

Education

I have completed A levels at Mendip studio school.